Guide to the Fidelis Zitterbart Manuscripts, 1868-1915 SC.1967.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Pauline: Schottish: No. 22, flute part (1 p.), clarinet 1 and 2 in B part (1 p.), trumpet 1 and 2 in B part (1 p.), horn 1 and 2 part (1 p.), trombone part (1 p.), violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), and cello and bass part (1 p.) (Box 51, Folder 9)
  Part of 'Dances, for small orchestra.' Brittle. Cover sheet (also first page of piano part) is torn in half (missing other half). Incomplete?
  - Pauline: Schottish - Parts: Flute, 1.
  - Pauline: Schottish - Parts: Clarinet 1 and 2 in B, 2.
  - Pauline: Schottish - Parts: Trumpet 1 and 2 in B, 3.
  - Pauline: Schottish - Parts: Horn 1 and 2, 4.
  - Pauline: Schottish - Parts: Trombone, 5.
  - Pauline: Schottish - Parts: Violin 1, 6.
  - Pauline: Schottish - Parts: Violin 2, 7.
  - Pauline: Schottish - Parts: Viola, 8.
  - Pauline: Schottish - Parts: Cello and Bass, 9.
- All Aboard: Galop: No. 23, flute part (1 p.), clarinet 1 and 2 part (1 p.), trumpet in B part (1 p.), horn 1 and 2 part (1 p.), trombone part (1 p.), violin 1 part (4 copies, each 1 p.), violin 2 part (2 copies, each 1 p.), viola part (2 copies, each 1 p.), cello and bass part (1 p.), cello part (2 copies each 1 p.), and bass part (2 copies, each 1 p.) (Box 51, Folder 10)
  Parts are in 2 different sizes: 31 cm. and 35 cm. The number "475" written in pencil on cover. "Opus 45" written in red inkon cover. VERY brittle. Part of 'Dances, for small orchestra.' Basso part damaged; some notes lost.
  - All Aboard - Parts: Flute, 1.
  - All Aboard - Parts: Clarinet 1 and 2 in B, 2.
  - All Aboard - Parts: Trumpet in B, 3.
  - All Aboard - Parts: Horn 1 and 2, 4.
  - All Aboard - Parts: Trombone, 5.
  - All Aboard - Parts: Violin 1, 6.
  - All Aboard - Parts: Violin 2, 7.
  - All Aboard - Parts: Viola, 8.
  - All Aboard - Parts: Cello and Bass, 9.
  - All Aboard - Parts: Cello, 10.
  - All Aboard - Parts: Bass, 11.
- Trixy,: for Orchestra, flute part (1 p.), oboe part (1 p.), clarinet 1 part (1 p.), clarinet 2 part (1 p.), bassoon part (1 p.), cornet 1 part (1 p.), cornet 2 part (1 p.), trombone part (1 p.), drum and triangle part (1 p.), horn 1 and 2 part (2 p.), violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), bass part (1 p.), and piano part (2 p) (Box 51, Folder 11)
  The number "472" written in pencil on wrapper. Outside cover very brittle.
  - Trixy - Parts: Flute, 1.
  - Trixy - Parts: Oboe, 2.
  - Trixy - Parts: Clarinet 1, 3.
  - Trixy - Parts: Clarinet 2, 4.
  - Trixy - Parts: Bassoon, 5.
  - Trixy - Parts: Cornet 1, 6.
  - Trixy - Parts: Cornet 2, 7.
  - Trixy - Parts: Trombone, 8.
  - Trixy - Parts: Drum and Triangle, 9.
  - Trixy - Parts: Horn 1 and 2, 10.
  - Trixy - Parts: Violin 1, 11.
  - Trixy - Parts: Violin 2, 12.
  - Trixy - Parts: Viola, 13.
  - Trixy - Parts: Violoncello, 14.
  - Trixy - Parts: Bass, 15.
  - Trixy - Parts: Piano, 16
- Gavotte: The Alvin: for Piano: [in F major], June 15, 1892; 3 p. of music (Box 51, Folder 12)
  Originally for violin and piano; arr. for solo piano. The number "263" penciled in on top-left t.p.
- Gavotte: The Alvin: for Violin and Piano, June 15, 1892; 1 score (3 p.), and violin part (1 p.) (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Gavotte - Score, June 15, 1892; 1.
  - Gavotte - Parts: Violin, June 15, 1892; 2.
- 2 Gavottes: for Orchestra, June 25, 1892; 1 score (7 p.), flute part (2 p.), oboe part (2 p.), clarinet 1 in C part (2 p.), clarinet 2 in C part (2 p.), cornet 1 and 2 in B part (2 p.), horn 1 and 2 part (2 p.), trombone part (2 p.), violin 1 part (2 copies, 2 and 1 p.), violin 2 part (2 copies, each 2 p.), viola part (2 p.), bass part (2 p.), and piano part (3 p.) (Box 51, Folder 14)
  No. 1 is incomplete. The number "479" written in pencil on wrapper. Score in oblong format is written in pencil. Dates differ on score: no. 1 dated 06/24/1892; no. 2 dated 06/28/1892. Contents: No. 1. The Alvin -- No. 2. Pittsburgh Electric Club.
  - 2 Gavottes - Score, June 25, 1892; 1.
  - 2 Gavottes - Parts: Flute, June 25, 1892; 2.
  - 2 Gavottes - Parts: Oboe, June 25, 1892; 3.
  - 2 Gavottes - Parts: Clarinet 1 in C, June 25, 1892; 4.
  - 2 Gavottes - Parts: Clarinet 2 in C, June 25, 1892; 5.
  - 2 Gavottes - Parts: Cornet 1 and 2 in B, June 25, 1892; 6.
  - 2 Gavottes - Parts: Horn 1 and 2, June 25, 1892; 7.
  - 2 Gavottes - Parts: Trombone, June 25, 1892; 8.
  - 2 Gavottes - Parts: Violin 1, June 25, 1892; 9.
  - 2 Gavottes - Parts: Violin 2, June 25, 1892; 10.
  - 2 Gavottes - Parts: Viola, June 25, 1892; 11.
  - 2 Gavottes - Parts: Bass, June 25, 1892; 12.
  - 2 Gavottes - Parts: Piano, June 25, 1892; 13.
- Base Ball: Galop: for Orchestra, June 23, 1892; 1 score (8 p.), flute part (1 p.), oboe part (1 p.), clarinet 1 and 2 in C part (1 p.), cornet 1 and 2 in B part (1 p.), horn part (1 p.), trombone part (1 p.), violin 1 part (2 copies, each 1 p.), violin 2 part (2 copies, each 1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), and bass part (1 p.) (Box 51, Folder 15)
  Score is in oblong format written in pencil. Title on score: Base Ball Gallop. Date on score: 06/28/1892. The number "483" written in pencil on wrapper. Illustrated cover and score. Wrapper is brittle.
  - Base Ball: Galop - Score, June 23, 1892; 1.
  - Base Ball: Galop - Parts: Flute, June 23, 1892; 2.
  - Base Ball: Galop - Parts: Oboe, June 23, 1892; 3.
  - Base Ball: Galop - Parts: Clarinet 1 and 2 in C, June 23, 1892; 4.
  - Base Ball: Galop - Parts: Cornet 1 and 2 in B, June 23, 1892; 5.
  - Base Ball: Galop - Parts: Horn, June 23, 1892; 6.
  - Base Ball: Galop - Parts: Trombone, June 23, 1892; 7.
  - Base Ball: Galop - Parts: Violin 1, June 23, 1892; 8.
  - Base Ball: Galop - Parts: Violin 2, June 23, 1892; 9.
  - Base Ball: Galop - Parts: Viola, June 23, 1892; 10.
  - Base Ball: Galop - Parts: Violoncello, June 23, 1892; 11.
  - Base Ball: Galop - Parts: Bass, June 23, 1892; 12.
- Up to the Moon: Galop: for Orchestra, 1 score (10 p.), flute part (2 p.), oboe part (2 p.), clarinet 1 in B part (2 p.), clarinet 2 in B part (2 p.), bassoon part (2 p.), cornet 1 part (2 p.), cornet 2 part (2 p.), horn 1 and 2 part (2 p.), trombone part (2 p.), drum part (2 p.), violin 1 part (2 copies, each 2 p.), violin 2 part (2 p.), viola part (2 p.), violoncello part (2 p.), bass part (2 p.), and piano part (3 p.) (Box 51, Folder 16)
  The number "482" written in pencil on cover.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Score, 1.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Flute, 2.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Oboe, 3.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Clarinet 1, 4.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Clarinet 2, 5.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Bassoon, 6.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Cornet 1, 7.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Cornet 2, 8.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Horn 1 and 2, 9.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Trombone, 10.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Drum, 11.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Violin 1, 12.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Violin 2, 13.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Viola, 14.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Violoncello, 15.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Bass, 16.
  - Up to the Moon: Galop - Parts: Piano, 17.
- Get a Move On: Galop, 1 score (9 p.), flute part (1 p.), oboe part (1 p.), clarinet part (1 p.), clarinet 2 part (1 p.), bassoon part (1 p.), cornet 1 part (1 p.), cornet 2 part (1 p.), horn 1 and 2 part (2 p.), trombone part (1 p.), drum part (1 p.), violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), bass part (1 p.), and piano part (2 p.) (Box 51, Folder 17)
  Score is in oblong format. Original title, "Clear the Track," is crossed off on cover, score and parts and replaced with "Get a Move On" in red ink.
  - Get a Move On - Score, 1.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Flute, 2.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Oboe, 3.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Clarinet 1, 4.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Clarinet 2, 5.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Bassoon, 6.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Cornet 1, 7.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Cornet 2, 8.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Horn 1 and 2, 9.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Trombone, 10.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Drum, 11.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Violin 1, 12.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Violin 2, 13.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Viola, 14.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Violoncello, 15.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Bass, 16.
  - Get a Move On - Parts: Piano, 17.
- Red Riding Hood: Polka: [for] Violin & Piano, 1 score (3 p.), and violin part (1 p.) (Box 52, Folder 1)
  Corrections by the composer in score and part in pencil and ink. At head of violin part: To Miss Florence Zitterbart.
  - Red Riding Hood - Score, 1.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Violin, 2.
- Red Riding-Hood: Polka: for Orchestra, 1 score (7 p.), flute part (1 p.), oboe part (1 p.), clarinet 1 part (1 p.), clarinet 2 part (1 p.), bassoon part (1 p.), cornet 1 part (1 p.), cornet 2 part (1 p.), horn 1 and 2 part (2 p.), trombone part (1 p.), drum and triangle part (1 p.), violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), and bass part (1 p.) (Box 52, Folder 2)
  Arrangement of the piece for violin and piano. It cannot be ascertained which version came first since neither is dated. The number "465" written in pencil on score. At head of title: To Miss Florence Zitterbart.
  - Red Riding Hood - Score, 1.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Flute, 2.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Oboe, 3.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Clarinet 1, 4.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Clarinet 2, 5.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Bassoon, 6.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Cornet 1, 7.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Cornet 2, 8.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Horn 1 and 2, 9.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Trombone, 10.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Drum and Triangle, 11.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Violin 1, 12.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Violin 2, 13.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Viola, 14.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Violoncello, 15.
  - Red Riding Hood - Parts: Bass, 16.
- The Whirlwind: Galop: for Orchestra, 1 score (13 p.), flute part (1 p.), oboe part (1 p.), clarinet 1 part (1 p.) clarinet 2 part (1 p.), bassoon part (1 p.), cornet 1 part (1 p.), cornet 2 part (1 p.), horn 1 and 2 part (2 p.), trombone part (1 p.), drum part (1 p.), violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), bass part (1 p.), and piano part (3 p.) (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - The Whirlwind - Score, 1.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Flute, 2.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Oboe, 3.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Clarinet 1, 4.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Clarinet 2, 5.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Bassoon, 6.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Cornet 1, 7.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Cornet 2, 8.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Horn 1 and 2, 9.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Trombone, 10.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Drum, 11.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Violin 1, 12.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Violin 2, 13.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Viola, 14.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Violoncello, 15.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Bass, 16.
  - The Whirlwind - Parts: Piano, 17.
- The Hustler: Galop: for Orchestra, April 21, 1892; 1 score (9 p.), flute part (1 p.), oboe part (1 p.), clarinet in C part (1 p.), cornet in A part (1 p.), horn part (1 p.), trombone part (1 p.), small drum part (1 p.), violin 1 part (2 copies, each 1 p.), violin 2 part (2 copies, each 1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), and bass part (1 p.) (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - The Hustler - Score, April 21, 1892; 1.
  - The Hustler - Parts: Flute, April 21, 1892; 2.
  - The Hustler - Parts: Oboe, April 21, 1892; 3.
  - The Hustler - Parts: Clarinet in C, April 21, 1892; 4.
  - The Hustler - Parts: Cornet in A, April 21, 1892; 5.
  - The Hustler - Parts: Horn, April 21, 1892; 6.
  - The Hustler - Parts: Trombone, April 21, 1892; 7.
  - The Hustler - Parts: Small Drum, April 21, 1892; 8.
  - The Hustler - Parts: Violin 1, April 21, 1892; 9.
  - The Hustler - Parts: Violin 2, April 21, 1892; 10.
  - The Hustler - Parts: Viola, April 21, 1892; 11.
  - The Hustler - Parts: Violoncello, April 21, 1892; 12.
  - The Hustler - Parts: Bass, April 21, 1892; 13.
- On the Boulevard: Galop: for Violin & Piano, 1 score (3 p.) (Box 52, Folder 5)
  Score in pencil. Working copy of the orchestrated version? Other instruments given in the score. Title is on the incomplete 2 Horns in F part for The Whirlwind.
- On the Boulevard: Galop: for Orchestra, 1 score (10 p.), flute part (1 p.), oboe part (1 p.), violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), and piano part (3 p.) (Box 52, Folder 6)
  The number "480" written in pencil on wrapper. Incomplete. Only includes parts for flute, oboe, violin I, violin II, viola and piano.
  - On the Boulevard - Score, 1.
  - On the Boulevard - Parts: Flute, 2.
  - On the Boulevard - Parts: Oboe, 3.
  - On the Boulevard - Parts: Violin 1, 4.
  - On the Boulevard - Parts: Violin 2, 5.
  - On the Boulevard - Parts: Viola, 6.
  - On the Boulevard - Parts: Piano, 7.
- Ballade Fantastique: in D Major: for Violoncello and Piano, January 11, 1915; 1 score (5 p.), and violincello part (1 p.) (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Ballade Fantastique - Score, January 11, 1915; 1.
  - Ballade Fantastique - Parts: Violoncello, 2.
- Episodes: From an Artist's Life: Concertstück: for Violoncello and Piano, January 25, 1909; 1 score (21 p.), and violoncello part (7 p.) (Box 52, Folder 8)
  The number "557" written in pencil on cover. At head of title: To Mr. Henri Merck. Date on bottom of t.p. given as 01/29/1909, but is crossed on and date of 01/25/1909 written in.
  - Episodes: From an Artist's Life - Score, January 25, 1909; 1.
  - Episodes: From an Artist's Life - Parts: Violoncello, January 25, 1909; 2.
- 10 Album Leaves: for Violoncello and Piano, 1 score (37 p.), and violoncello part (16 p.) (Box 52, Folder 9)
  The number "556" written in pencil on cover. The number "10" is pasted in on t.p. The number "6" pasted on caption of score and part. At head of title: To Miss Florence Zitterbart. Only no. 8-10 are dated. Contents: 1. Allegretto -- 2. Presto -- 3. Andante cantabile -- 4. Allegro giojoso -- 5. Traumgebilde: Andante amoroso -- 6. Morceau: Amongst the roses -- 7. Album leaves -- 8. Allegro spiritoso (09/22/1907) -- 9. Song without words: Rememberance (09/24/1907) -- 10. Andante moso-grazioso et molto espressione (10/02/1907).
  - 10 Album Leaves - Score, 1.
  - 10 Album Leaves - Parts: Violoncello, 2.
- VI Fantasie Stücke: [no.] 5: [for] Violoncello and Piano, 1 score (18 p.), and violoncello part (7 p.) (Box 52, Folder 10)
  The number "547" written in pencil on score. Contents: 1. Moderato -- 2. Allegretto con moto -- 3. Adagio cantabile -- 4. Andante cantabile (German. Song without words) -- 5. Finale: Allegro-con-moto -- 6. Romanza: Andante amoroso
  - VI Fantasie Stücke - Score, 1.
  - VI Fantasie Stücke - Parts: Violoncello, 2.
- Menuetto: for Cello or Viola and Piano, 1 score (3 p.), viola part (1 p.), and cello part (1 p.) (Box 52, Folder 11)
  On caption: Edited by W.K. Steiner (in his hand?). Part for viola (transposed violoncello part) is on verso of violoncello part.
  - Menuetto - Score, 1.
  - Menuetto - Parts: Viola and Cello, 2.
- The Fountain: Morceau: in D Major: [for] Violoncello and Piano, October 4, 1907; 1 score (5 p.), and violoncello part (1 p.) (Box 52, Folder 12)
  The number "548" written in pencil on score.
  - The Fountain - Score, October 4, 1907; 1.
  - The Fountain - Parts: Violoncello, October 4, 1907; 2.
- Elegie: in C Major: for Violoncello and Piano, February 10, 1914; 1 score (5 p.), and violoncello part (1 p.) (Box 52, Folder 13)
  The number "549" written in pencil on cover.
  - Elegie - Score, February 10, 1914; 1.
  - Elegie - Parts: Violoncello, February 10, 1914; 2.
- Romanza Fantastique: in F Major: for Violoncello and Piano, October 16, 1911; 1 score (4 p.), and violoncello part (2 p.) (Box 52, Folder 14)
  The number "550" written in pencil on wrapper. At head of title: To Mr. Joseph Derdeyn.
  - Romanza Fantastique - Score, October 16, 1911; 1.
  - Romanza Fantastique - Parts: Violoncello, October 16, 1911; 2.
- Meditation: [no.] 17: in A Major: [for] Violoncello and Piano, October 21, 1903; 1 score (3 p.), and violoncello part (1 p.) (Box 52, Folder 15)
  The number "551" written in pencil on score.
  - Meditation: [no.] 17 - Score, October 21, 1903; 1.
  - Meditation: [no.] 17 - Parts: Violoncello, October 21, 1903; 2.
- Saltarella: [for] Violoncello and Piano, March 18, 1913; 1 score (6 p.), and violoncello part (2 p.) (Box 53, Folder 1)
  The number "552" written in pencil on cover of part.
  - Saltarella - Score, March 18, 1913; 1.
  - Saltarella - Parts: Violoncello, March 18, 1913; 2.
- 5 Morceaus: for Violoncello and Piano, February 28, 1907; 1 score (18 p.), and violoncello part (5 p.) (Box 53, Folder 2)
  The number "554" written in pencil on cover. At head of title: To Mr. Frederick Goerner. Contents: 1. A moonlight scene -- 2. Reverie -- 3. Romanza -- 4. Swansong -- 5. Slumbersong.
  - 5 Morceaus - Score, February 28, 1907; 1.
  - 5 Morceaus - Parts: Violoncello, February 28, 1907; 2.
- 3 Morceau's: [for] Violoncello et Piano: [in Eb major], 1 score (7 p.), and violoncello part (3 p.) (Box 53, Folder 3)
  The number "4" pasted in on score and part; there are no other morceaus for this combination. The number "402" penciled in on score. The number "661" penciled in on violoncello part.
  - 3 Morceau's - Score, 1.
  - 3 Morceau's - Parts: Violoncello, 2.
- [4 pieces]: for Violoncello and Piano, October 14-21, 1914; 4 scores, each piece binded separately, (3, 4, 4, and 3 p.), and violoncello part (4 p.) (Box 53, Folder 4)
  The number "555" written in pencil on wrapper. Individual dates given on score and part. At head of title: To Mr. Walter Y. Sprenkle. Contents: 1. Serenade (in G major; 10/14/1914) -- 2. Reverie (in Eb major; 10/17/1914) 3. Romanza (in Bb major; 10/19/1914) -- 4. Notturno (in D major; 10/21/1914).
  - [4 pieces] - Scores, October 14-21, 1914; 1.
  - [4 pieces] - Parts: Violoncello, October 14-21, 1914; 2.
- The Rug of Imam: Noveletic Sketch: in D Major: for Violin, Viola and Piano, April 30, 1912; 1 score (8 p.), violin part (2 p.), viola part (2 p.) (Box 53, Folder 5)
  The number "215" written in pencil on cover. Contains hanwritten working copy.(11 pgs).
  - The Rug of Imam - Score, April 30, 1912; 1.
  - The Rug of Imam - Parts: Violin, April 30, 1912; 2.
  - The Rug of Imam - Parts: Viola, April 30, 1912; 3.
- Brauns Picture: Salonstück: [for] Violin, Viola and Piano, April 14, 1894; 1 score (2 p.), violine part (1 p.), and viola part (1 p.) (Box 53, Folder 6)
  The number "213" written in pencil on score. The number "25" pasted on score. The number "26" pasted on violin part but crossed out and "25" written in pencil. Score is incomplete; only mm. 1-46 of the 1st movement.
  - Brauns Picture - Score, April 14, 1894; 1.
  - Brauns Picture - Parts: Violine, April 14, 1894; 2.
  - Brauns Picture - Parts: Viola, April 14, 1894; 3.
- Youth's Voyage: Salonstück: [for violin, viola and] Piano, September 20, 1893; 1 score (7 p.), violine part (2 p.), and viola part (2 p.) (Box 53, Folder 7)
  The number "212" written in pencil on score.
  - Youth's Voyage - Score, September 20, 1893; 1.
  - Youth's Voyage - Parts: Violine, September 20, 1893; 1.
  - Youth's Voyage - Parts: Viola, September 20, 1893; 2.
- Bolero: [for violin, viola and] Piano, June 6, 1894; 1 score (7 p.), violine part (2 p.), and viola part (2 p.) (Box 53, Folder 8)
  The number "211" written in pencil on score. The number "22" pasted in on score and parts.
  - Bolero - Score, June 6, 1894; 1.
  - Bolero - Violine, June 6, 1894; 2.
  - Bolero - Viola, June 6, 1894; 3.
- Berceuse: [for violin, viola and] Piano, December 20, 1893; 1 score (9 p.), violine part (2 p.), and viola part (2 p.) (Box 53, Folder 9)
  The number "210" written in pencil on score. The number "24" pasted in on score and parts.
  - Berceuse - Score, December 20, 1893; 1.
  - Berceuse - Parts: Violine, December 20, 1893; 2.
  - Berceuse - Parts: Viola, December 20, 1893; 3.
- The Ballet: [no.] 1: [for violin, viola and] Piano, October 3, 1893; 1 score (19 p.), violine part (4 p.), and viola part (4 p.) (Box 53, Folder 10)
  The number "12" pasted in on score and parts.The number "209" written in pencil on score. Tempo and articulation indications written in pencil throughout score. Contents: 1. Allegro-agitato e andante-grazioso -- 2. Allegretto-scherzando -- 3. Mazurka a la bayadere.
  - The Ballet: [no.] 1 - Score, October 3, 1893; 1.
  - The Ballet: [no.] 1 - Parts: Violine, October 3, 1893; 2.
  - The Ballet: [no.] 1 - Parts: Viola, October 3, 1893; 3.
- The Ballet: No. 2: [for violin, viola and] Piano, 1 score (20 p.), violine part (6 p.), and viola part (5 p.) (Box 53, Folder 11)
  The number "205" written in pencil on score. The number "13" pasted in on score and parts. Contents: 1. Andante-grazioso -- 2. Allegretto-giojoso -- 3. The genie dance.
  - The Ballet: No. 2 - Score, 1.
  - The Ballet: No. 2 - Parts: Violine, 2.
  - The Ballet: No. 2 - Parts: Viola, 3.
- Tarantella: [for] Violin, Viola [and] Piano, August 8, 1893; 1 score (9 p.), violine part (3 p.), and viola part (2 p.) (Box 53, Folder 12)
  The number "208" written in pencil on score. The number "19" pasted in on score and parts.
  - Tarantella - Score, August 8, 1893; 1.
  - Tarantella - Parts: Violine, August 8, 1893; 2.
  - Tarantella - Parts: Viola, August 8, 1893; 3.
- Fantastic Sketch: in D Minor: Rip van Winkle: for Violin, Viola and Piano, December 30, 1905; 1 score (26 p.), violin part (7 p.), and viola part (7 p.) (Box 53, Folder 13)
  The number "200" written in pencil on cover. At head of title: To Mr. William Speer. Contents: 1. Moderato con moto -- 2. March of the Braunies -- 3. Finale: Allegro spiritoso.
  - Fantastic Sketch - Score, December 30, 1905; 1.
  - Fantastic Sketch - Violin, December 30, 1905; 2.
  - Fantastic Sketch - Viola, December 30, 1905; 3.
- Concertante: [no.] 13: in D Major: The New Spring: for Violin, Viola and Piano, July 18, 1902; 1 score (20 p.), violin part (5 p.), and viola part (5 p.) (Box 53, Folder 14)
  The number "199" written in pencil on cover. The number "13" pasted in on score and parts. Photograph of 2 men sitting beneath a tree pasted on cover. Contents: 1. The discovery: Allegro-agitato; The spring: Andante cantabile -- 2. The meditation: Adagio-sentimentale-- 3. Retrospection: Finale, Allegro-spiritoso.
  - Concertante - Score, July 18, 1902; 1.
  - Concertante - Parts: Violin, July 18, 1902; 2.
  - Concertante - Parts: Viola, July 18, 1902; 3.
- Scherzo: [no. 1]: in Bb Minor: [for violin, viola and] Piano, April 16, 1894; 1 score (8 p.), violine part (2 p.), and viola part (2 p.) (Box 53, Folder 15)
  The number "198" written in pencil on score. The number "14" pasted in on score and parts. The "No. 1" is indicated only on the parts.
  - Scherzo: [no. 1] - Score, April 16, 1894; 1.
  - Scherzo: [no. 1] - Parts: Violine, April 16, 1894; 2.
  - Scherzo: [no. 1] - Parts: Viola, April 16, 1894; 3.
- Scherzo: No. 2: in D Minor: [for violin, viola and] Piano, April 30, 1894; 1 score (9 p.), violine part (2 p.), viola part (2 p.) (Box 53, Folder 16)
  The number "197" written in pencil on score. The number "15" pasted in on score and parts.
  - Scherzo: No. 2 - Score, April 30, 1894; 1.
  - Scherzo: No. 2 - Parts: Violine, April 30, 1894; 2.
  - Scherzo: No. 2 - Parts: Viola, April 30, 1894; 3.
- Adagio et Scherzo: [for violin, viola and] Piano, 1 score (10 p.), violine part (3 p.), and viola part (2 p.) (Box 53, Folder 17)
  The number "196" written in pencil on score. The number "16" pasted in or written in pencil on score and parts.
  - Adagio et Scherzo - Score, 1.
  - Adagio et Scherzo - Parts: Violine, 2.